<resources>
    <string name="app_name">uSafeNH</string>

    <string name="UNH">University of New Hampshire</string>
    <string name="Saint_Anselm">Saint Anselm College</string>
    <string name="Keene_State">Keene State College</string>
    <string name="White_Mountain">White Mountain Community College</string>
    <string name="Local_police">Local Police</string>
    <string name="Campus_resources">Campus Resources</string>
    <string name="Local_hospital">Local Hospitals</string>
    <string name="Crisis_centers">Crisis Centers</string>
    <string name="help_now_button">Get Help Now</string>
    <string name="help_someone">Help Someone You Know</string>
    <string name="faq">FAQ</string>
    <string name="faq_self">FAQ for Myself</string>

    <string name="details_button">View Details</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="usafe">uSafeNH</string>
    <string name="usafe_website">http://www.nhcadsv.org/</string>

    <string name="Invalid_info">No info found.</string>

    <string name="UNH_Local_police">
        UNH Police Department\n
        Address:\n
        \t\t18 Waterworks Road, Durham, NH, 03824\n
        Phone:\n
        \t\t(603)-862-1427
    </string>
    <string name="UNH_Campus_resources">
        Campus Safety\n
        Phone:\n
        \t\t(603)-862-1427\n
        In Emergency: 911\n
        Website:\n
        \t\thttp://www.unh.edu/upd
    </string>
    <string name="UNH_Local_hospital">
        Wentworth-Douglas Hospital\n
        Address:\n
        \t\t789 Central Ave, Dover, NH, 03820\n
        Phone:\n
        \t\t(603)-742-5252\n
        Website:\n
        \t\thttp://www.wdhospital.com/Contact
    </string>
    <string name="UNH_Crisis_centers">
        Sexual Harrassment and Rape Prevention Program (SHARPP)\n
        Address:\n
        \t\t8 Ballard Street, Durham, NH, 03824\n
        Phone:\n
        \t\t1-888-271-7233\n
        Website:\n
        \t\thttp://www.unh.edu/sharpp/
    </string>

    <string name="Keene_State_Local_police">
        Keene Police Department\n
        Address:\n
        \t\t400 Marlboro St., Keene, NH 03431\n
        Contact:\n
        \t\t(603)-357-9815
    </string>
    <string name="Keene_State_Campus_resources">
        Counseling Center\n
        Address:\n
        \t\tElliot Center (3rd Floor) / 229 Main St., Keene, NH 03435\n
        Contact:\n
        \t\t(603)-358-2437 / Crisis Line: 603-358-2436
    </string>
    <string name="Keene_State_Local_hospital">
        Cheshire Medical Center\n
        Address:\n
        \t\t580 Court St., Keene, NH 03431\n
        Contact:\n
        \t\t(603)-354-6600
    </string>
    <string name="Keene_State_Crisis_centers">
        Monadnock Center for Violence Prevention (MCVP):\n
        Address:\n
        \t\t12 Court St., Keene, NH 03431\n
        Contact:\n
        \t\t(603)-352-3782
    </string>

    <string name="Saint_Anselm_Local_police">
        Gofftstown Police Department \n
        Address:\n
        \t\t 326 Mast Rd, Gofftstown, NH 03045\n
        Contact:\n
        \t\t(603)-497-4858
    </string>
    <string name="Saint_Anselm_Campus_resources">
        Campus Safety \n
        Contact:\n
        \t\t(603)-641-7000 or ext x555 \n
        Website:\n
        \t\thttp://www.anselm.edu/Current-Students/Campus-Safety-and-Parking.htm
    </string>
    <string name="Saint_Anselm_Local_hospital">
        Catholic Medical Center \n
        Address:\n
        \t\t100 McGregor Street, Manchester, NH, 03102\n
        Contact:\n
        \t\t800-437-9666
    </string>
    <string name="Saint_Anselm_Crisis_centers">
        YWCA Crisis Service\n
        Contact:\n
        \t\t(603)-668-2299\n
        Website:\n
        \t\twww.ywcanh.org\n
        Address:\n
        \t\t72 Concord Street Manchester, NH, 03101\n\n
        Serves Northern HIllsborough County, including the greater Manchester area.
    </string>

    <string name="White_Mountain_Local_police">
        Berlin Police Department\n
        Address:\n
        \t\t\135 Green St., Berlin, NH, 03570\n
        Contact:\n
        \t\t(603)-752-3131
    </string>
    <string name="White_Mountain_Campus_resources">
        Campus Safety\n
        Contact:\n
        \t\t9-911(using a campus phone)\n
        Website:\n
        \t\thttp://wmcc.edu/student-services/campus-safety
    </string>
    <string name="White_Mountain_Local_hospital">
        Androscoggin Valley Hospital\n
        Address:\n
        \t\t59 Page Hill Rd., Berlin, NH, 03570\n
        Contact:\n
        \t\t(603)-752-2200
    </string>
    <string name="White_Mountain_Crisis_centers">
        Response to Sexual and Domestic Violence\n
        Contact:\n
        \t\t1-866-662-4220\n
        Website\n
        \t\twww.coosfamilyhealth.org/response.html\n
        Address:\n
        \t\t54 Willow Street Berlin, NH, 03570\n\n
        Serves Coos County.
    </string>

    <!--FAQ Categories-->
    <string name="Category_I_Was_Just">I was just assaulted and what should I do?</string>
    <string name="Category_What_Is">What is ...</string>
    <string name="Category_College_Policy">College policy and support groups</string>
    <string name="Category_Helping_Others">Helping others</string>

    <!--FAQ Question and Answers-->
    <!-- List for Myself FAQ: 1-11-->
    <!-- List for Friend of Survivor: 12,2,13,14,15,10-->
    <!-- List for Family of Survivor:12,2,16,17,18,19,10,20,21-->
    <!-- List for Faculty and Staff:12,2,22,23,24,25,26,27-->
    <!-- List for Prospective Students:12,2,28,29,30,31-->
    <!-- List for Off Campus Community members:12,2,32,33,34-->
    <string name="q1">Was I sexually assaulted?</string>
    <string name="a1">\n• The term sexual assault refers to any sexual contact that occurs without explicit consent. Sexual assault can take many forms, but it is never the victim’s fault. Forms of sexual assault include: penetration of the victim’s body (also known as rape), attempted rape, forcing a victim to perform sexual acts, and fondling or unwanted sexual touching.</string>
    <string name="q2">What is consent?</string>
    <string name="a2"> \n• Consent is two people (or more) deciding together to do the same thing, at the same time, in the same way, with each other, without coercion, intimidation, manipulation, physical force, power disparity, mental illness, incapacitation, intoxication, and/or threats. \n \n
        • Consent is active, not passive. There must always be active consent on both sides. A person who consents has the right to change their mind at any point in time. If they do, the sexual activity must stop immediately. \n \n
        • In New Hampshire, the legal age of consent is 16.</string>
    <string name="q3">Is it still considered sexual assault if it was my acquaintance, friend, or romantic partner?</string>
    <string name="a3">\n• Yes. Approximately two thirds of all sexual assaults are perpetrated by someone who the survivor knows. \n \n
        [SOURCE: U.S. Department of Justice, National Crime Victimization Study: 2009-2013]</string>
    <string name="q4">I was just sexually assaulted. What do I do?</string>
    <string name="a4">\n• Go to a safe place. \n \n
        • If you want to report the crime, notify the police immediately. Reporting the crime can help you regain a sense of personal power and control. \n \n
        • Call a friend, a family member, or someone else you trust who can be with you and provide support. \n \n
        • Preserve all physical evidence of the assault. Do not shower, bathe, douche, eat, drink, wash your hands, or brush your teeth until after you have had a medical examination. Save all of the clothing you were wearing at the time of the assault. Do not clean or disturb anything in the area where the assault occurred. \n \n
        • Seek medical care as soon as possible. Go to a hospital emergency department or doctor\'s office. Even if you think you do not have any physical injuries, it is important to hae a medical examination and discuss with a health care provider the risk of exposure to sexually transmitted infections and the possibility of pregnancy resulting from the sexual assault. Having a medical exam is also a way for you to preserve physical evidence of a sexual assault. \n\n
        • If you suspect that you may have been given a "rape drug", ask the hospital or clinic where you receive medical care to take a urine sample. Drugs, such as Rophynol and GHB, are more likely to be detected in urine than in the blood. \n\n
        • After a sexual assault, you have a lot of choices and decisions to make about getting medical care, making a police report, and informing others. You may have concerns about the impact of the assault and the reactions of friends and family members. You can get the information by calling a rape crisis center, a hotline, or other victim assistance agencies. \n\n
        [SOURCE: Adapted from the Rape, Abus, and Incest National Network[RAINN]Website for N.H. College Students]</string>
    <string name="q5">How do I file a report? What are my options?</string>
    <string name="a5">\n <b>Report to Law Enforcement</b> \n\n
        • An officer will meet with you in a safe place to take a brief, initial report. They will also encourage you to seek medical attention to ensure that you receive proper care and follow up. They will assist you in obtaining medical care at the appropriate facility. The officer will also ensure that a local crisis center advocate is contacted to be with you for as long as you would like. \n\n
        • Arrangements will be made with you to meet in the near future with the investigating officer or detective assigned to follow up on the initial report. this will involve a more detailed interview about what happened. NH best practice allows for a crisis center advocate to be present with the victim, if the victim desires, during the interview process. \n\n
        • An investigative follow up will occur with the collection of evidence, contact with potential witnesses and the suspect, as well as a complete and thorough documentation. \n\n
        • At any point during the investigation, law enforcement may consult with a prosecutor to determine the next steps, make decisions about a possible arrest and/or prosecution of the crime. The victim should be kept informed about the status of their case and can also contact the investigator if they have questions.\n\n\n
        <b>Have A Forensic Exam Kit Done Anonymously</b> \n\n
        • A person who is 18 years old or more and has been sexually assaulted in New Hampshire can contact law enforcement to ask questions about the reporting process without identifying themselves in an effort to determine if they want o come forward and make a formal report. They may also provide some information about what happened to them during this conversation. However, law enforcement cannot proceed with an investigation without an identified victim. \n\n
        • Not Report to law enforcement.</string>
    <string name="q6">How long do I have to report?</string>
    <string name="a6">\n• In New Hampshire, the statute of limitations for Aggravated Felonious Sexual Assault and Felonious Sexual Assault is 6 years. \n\n
        • The statute of limitations for Sexual Assault is 1 year.
        • If the victim is under the age of 18 at the time of their assault, the statute of limitations is 22 years after their 18th birthday (until age 40).</string>
    <string name="q7">What will happen if I go to the hospital?</string>
    <string name="a7">\n <b>Before Going to The Hospital </b>\n\n
        • If possible, avoid showering, bathing, using feminine hygiene products, washing your hands, or brushing your teeth before arrival in order to preserve evidence.
        • DNA evidence is most reliably collected within 72 hours. However, forensic exams can be performed up to five days after an assault. \n \n
        • Bring a change of clothing with you if you are able to. Any clothing worn at the time of the attack may be collected as evidence. \n\n
        • You may wish to bring a trusted friend or family member with you for support. \n\n
        • A local crisis center advocate will be available to provide free, confidential emotional support, information, and resources throughout the process. \n\n\n
        <b>The Forensic Examination</b> \n \n
        • The forensic exam will only be conducted with your informed consent. \n\n
        • An advocate or someone you trust can be present with you for support during the exam if you wish. \n\n
        • Your medical-forensic history will be collected for the purpose of diagnosis and treatment. \n\n
        • There will be a full body physical examination, including a detailed genital exam looking for trauma. \n\n
        • You may choose not to proceed with any part of the examination that you are uncomfortable with, as this should not be a retraumatizing experience. \n\n
        [SOURCE: http://nhcadsv.org/hospital_exam.cfm</string>
    <string name="q8">If I go through the forensic exam do I have to report to the police? Will the hospital call the police?</string>
    <string name="a8">\n• No. If you go to the hospital, you will receive medical care and still be able to decide whether or not you wish to report to law enforcement if you are over the age of 18. \n\n
        • You also have the option to have forensic evidence collected anonymously. You will be given an anonymous serial number for the exam kit, which will be stored at the state lab, and have 60 days to file a report with law enforcement. \n\n
        • After 60 days, you may still file a report with law enforcement, but there is no guarantee that evidence from the kit will be preserved.\n\n
    [SOURCE: http://doj.nh.gov/criminal/victim-assistance/documents/acute-care-protocol.pdf]</string>
    <string name="q9">How much will it cost?</string>
    <string name="a9">\n• You will not be charged for the sexual assault examination. If you do not have insurance or decide not to report to law enforcment, all costs will be covered by the NH Attorney General\'s Office. \n\n
        • You will receive a voucher for a follow-up exam. \n\n
        • If you decide to report to law enforcement, you may also be reimbursed for follow-up care and ongoing crime-related expenses (e.g., mental health treatment) after you leave the hospital. \n\n
        For More Information, Contact \n\n
        New Hampshire Victims Compensation Program \n
        Office of the Attorney General\n
        33 Capitol Street\n
        Concord, NH 03301-6397\n
        Phone:(603) 271-1284\n
        Toll Free: 1-800-300-4500 (in NH only)\n
        TDD Access Relay NH: 1-800-735-2964 \n
        Email: victimcomp@doj.nh.gov</string>
    <string name="q10">Where can I find my college\'s policies on sexual assault?</string>
    <string name="a10">\n• You can find your college\'s campus specific information in the student handbook.</string>
    <string name="q11">I am a survivor of sexual assault and need someone to talk to. What supports are available to me, and will what I say remain confidential?</string>
    <string name="a11">\n <b>Support is Campus Specific</b>\n\n
        • Counseling centers(if applicable) and Support groups(if applicable) are available.\n\n
        • You may with to speak with the Title IX Coordinator at your college. the Title IX Coordinator can be a very helpful resource. However, they will be required to file a report by law if you disclose that you have been sexually assaulted. \n\n
        • Confidential advocates from your local crisis center can be reached anytime of the day or night.</string>
    <string name ="q12">What is sexual assault?</string>
    <string name ="a12">• The term sexual assault refers to any sexual contact that occurs without explicit consent. Sexual assault can take many forms, but it is never the victim\'s fault. Some forms of sexual assault include penetration of the victim\'s body (also known as rape), attempted rape, forcing a victim to perform sexual acts, and fondling or unwanted sexual touching.</string>
    <string name ="q13">My friend was just sexually assaulted. What do I do?</string>
    <string name ="a13">• Ask your friend if they are safe now, especially if they told you by phone or text.\n\n
        • Listen to and support your friend. \n\n
        • Believe your friend. \n\n
        • Reassure your friend that they are not to blame in any way. \n\n
        • Encourage your friend to seek medical attention, but ultimately respect their decision if they are not ready. Offer information and support but do not force your friend to do anything they do not want to do. \n\n
        • If your friend plans to seek medical care or file a report, offer to go with them.</string>
    <string name ="q14">How can I support a friend who has been sexually assaulted?</string>
    <string name ="a14">• Listen without interrupting.\n\n
        • Believe your friend.\n\n
        • Remain calm and non-judgemental.\n\n
        • Do not interrogate. Allow your friend to open up to you on their own terms.\n\n
        • Reassure your friend that this was not their fault and they are not to blame in any way.\n\n
        • Ask how you can help support them.\n\n
        • If your friend plans to seek medical care or file a report, offer to go with them.\n\n
        • Encourage your friend to seek support, but ultimately respect your friend\'s decision if they are not ready.\n\n
        • Respect your friend\'s privacy.\n\n
        • Encourage your friend to practice good self-care, and remember that it is important to take care of yourself as well.</string>
    <string name ="q15">Is there anyone on campus that I can talk to for support?</string>
    <string name ="a15">• It can be hard to know what to do to help a friend who has been sexually assaulted. You may feel angry, confused and helpless. There are people you can talk to. The counseling center on your campus (if applicable) can provide confidential support.</string>
    <string name ="q16">How can I talk about sexual assault prevention with my child or family member?</string>
    <string name ="a16">• It can be difficult to talk about sexual assault with your child or family member.\n\n
        <b>Some Talking Points Include:</b>\n\n
        • Educate yourself about sexual assault in the college setting.\n\n
        • Discuss the importance of consent. Explain that it is more than no means no.\n\n
        • Plan for safety in advance with them. Strategize about what to do in a potentially dangerous situation.\n\n
        • Emphasize that there is never an excuse for sexual assault and that survivors are never to blame.\n\n
        • Encourage your student to get involved with sexual assault prevention on campus.\n\n
        • Let them know that you will always be there for them and that they can come to you no matter what.</string>
    <string name ="q17">My child or family member was sexually assaulted, how am I supposed to react?</string>
    <string name ="a17">• It can be very difficult and overwhelming to hear that your child or family member has been sexually assaulted. The  most important thing you can do is to help your college student feel safe and supported. Anger confusion, sadness, and helplessness are all normal emotions to be experiencing right  now. Remember that it is important to take care of yourself and resources are available for you as well.</string>
    <string name ="q18">My child or family member was sexually assaulted, what can I do to be supportive?</string>
    <string name ="a18">• Listen without interrupting.\n\n
        • Believe them.\n\n
        • Remain calm and non-judgemental.\n\n
        • Do not interrogate. Allow them to open up to you on their own terms.\n\n
        • Reassure them that this was not their fault and they are not to blame in any way.\n\n
        • Ask how you can help support them.\n\n
        • If they plan to seek medical care or file a report, offer to go with them.\n\n
        • Encourage them to seek support, but ultimately respect their decision if they are not ready.\n\n
        • Respect their privacy.\n\n
        • Encourage them to practice good self-care, and remember that it is important to take care of yourself as well.</string>
    <string name ="q19">My child or family member was sexually assaulted, where can I receive support?</string>
    <string name ="a19">• Reach out to your local crisis center. 24 hour hotlines are available throughout the state. Advocates can provide you with free, confidential support and information about resources.</string>
    <string name ="q20">What is being done to address sexual assault on college campuses?</string>
    <string name ="a20">• Overview of statewide and national efforts\n\n
        • Campus specific efforts\n\n
        • Title IX Coordinator and other resources.</string>
    <string name ="q21">My family member/child is looking to or plans to attend this college. Where can I find information about sexual assault on this campus?</string>
    <string name ="a21">• Campus specific links.</string>
    <string name ="q22">A student disclosed to me that she/he was assaulted. What do I do?</string>
    <string name ="a22">• Listen without interrupting.\n\n
        • Believe them.\n\n
        • Remain calm and non-judgemental.\n\n
        • Do not interrogate. Allow them to open up to you on their own terms.\n\n
        • Reassure them that this was not their fault and they are not to blame in any way.\n\n
        • Ask how you can help support them.\n\n
        • If they plan to seek medical care or file a report, offer to go with them.\n\n
        • Encourage them to seek support, but ultimately respect their decision if they are not ready.\n\n
        • Respect their privacy. However, if you are a mandated reporter, follow protocol. </string>
    <string name ="q23">Who is a mandated reporter?</string>
    <string name ="a23">• Campus-specific mandated reporting protocols.</string>
    <string name ="q24">As a mandated reporter, what am I required to report?</string>
    <string name ="a24">• Campus specific mandated reporting protocols.</string>
    <string name ="q25">I overheard someone say that a student was sexually assaulted. What should I do?</string>
    <string name ="a25">• Campus-specific mandated reporting protocols.</string>
    <string name ="q26">How can I support a student who has been sexually assaulted?</string>
    <string name ="a26">• Listen without interrupting.\n\n
        • Believe them.\n\n
        • Remain calm and non-judgemental.\n\n
        • Do not interrogate. Allow them to open up to you on their own terms.\n\n
        • Reassure them that this was not their fault and they are not to blame in any way.\n\n
        • Ask how you can help support them.\n\n
        • If they plan to seek medical care or file a report, offer to go with them.\n\n
        • Encourage them to seek support, but ultimately respect their decision if they are not ready.\n\n
        • Respect your friend\'s privacy.\n\n
        • Encourage them to practice good self-care.</string>
    <string name ="q27">I am a faculty or staff member and I am experiencing or have experienced sexual assault, sexual harassment, intimate partner violence, and/or stalking. What resources are available for me?</string>
    <string name ="a27">• Campus-specific resources.</string>
    <string name ="q28">Are there ways to reduce my risk of sexual assault?</string>
    <string name ="a28"> <b>It is important to remember that sexual assault survivors are never to blame, but there are steps that you can take to increase your safety on campus.</b>\n\n
        • Be aware of your surroundings.\n\n
        • Try to avoid isolated areas where it may be difficult to get help.\n\n
        • Make sure your cell phone is with you and charged.\n\n
        • Bring a friend with you to parties and social gatherings. Agree to stick together and watch out for each other.\n\n
        • Keep an eye on your drink at parties and social gatherings. Do not accept drinks from people you do not know.\n\n
        • Trust your gut.</string>
    <string name ="q29">Where can I find information and statistics about sexual assault on campus?</string>
    <string name ="a29">• Campus specific links.\n\n
        •Clery Reports: Also provide information on the reporting process and the meaning of statistics.</string>
    <string name ="q30">I was sexually assaulted in the past. Are there resources available for me on campus?</string>
    <string name ="a30"><b>Campus-specific:</b>\n\n
        • Campus counseling center(if applicable).\n\n
        • Local crisis center.</string>
    <string name ="q31">How can I help with preventing and raising awareness about sexual assault on campus?</string>
    <string name ="a31"><b>Campus specific:</b>\n\n
        • Info about sexual assault awareness groups/events, etc.\n\n
        • You\'re Not Alone\n\n
        • Know your Title IX.
         </string>
    <string name ="q32">What should I do if a student discloses to me that they have been sexually assaulted?</string>
    <string name ="a32">• Listen and offer support.\n\n
        • Believe them.\n\n
        • Avoid judgement.\n\n
        • Will depend on role and relationship.</string>
    <string name ="q33">How can I support a sexual assault survivor?</string>
    <string name ="a33">• Listen and offer support.\n\n
        • Will depend on role and relationship.</string>
    <string name ="q34">What is the college doing about sexual assault?</string>
    <string name ="a34"><b>Campus Specific</b></string>


</resources>
